<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admin &#8211; CPalms</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/admin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 20:08:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/live-favicon.jpg</url>
	<title>admin &#8211; CPalms</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shah Rukh Khan to Reunite With Sanjay Leela Bhansali After 22 Years</title>
		<link>/shah-rukh-khan-to-reunite-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-after-22-years/</link>
					<comments>/shah-rukh-khan-to-reunite-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-after-22-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 14:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan and Sanjay Leela Bhansali collaborated on the blockbuster film &#8220;Devdas&#8221; 22 years ago. According to the latest reports, the duo is likely to reunite for another film soon. Bhansali initially announced his film &#8220;Inshallah&#8221; with Salman Khan...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Shah Rukh Khan and Sanjay Leela Bhansali collaborated on the blockbuster film &#8220;Devdas&#8221; 22 years ago. According to the latest reports, the duo is likely to reunite for another film soon. Bhansali initially announced his film &#8220;Inshallah&#8221; with Salman Khan and Alia Bhatt in 2019; however, the film which was slated for a theatrical release in 2020, did not commence shooting. The latest news regarding the film is that Bhansali has put a hold on his dream project &#8220;Baiju Bawra&#8221;, starring Ranveer Singh, as he is now keen on directing &#8220;Inshallah&#8221; with Shah Rukh Khan, according to a report on India.com.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>‘Jawan’, ‘Pathaan’ to compete with Hollywood action films for Vulture’s Stunt Awards</strong><br />
Several Indian media outlets have reported that the &#8220;Dunki&#8221; actor and Bhansali have already had multiple meetings regarding this film. The light-hearted romantic comedy is expected to be made soon. Reports also suggest that the lead female role might be played by Deepika Padukone instead of Alia Bhatt. The storyline of &#8220;Inshallah&#8221; centres on a couple spanning different generations who develop feelings for each other. A man in his forties experiences love for a woman younger than him, prompted by his bedridden father&#8217;s condition. The father decides to transfer his wealth to his son, but with the condition that the son must fall in love and improve his lifestyle as per the father&#8217;s wish. Reports also hint that the production has already begun, and fans might receive the announcement of &#8220;Inshallah&#8221; very soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/shah-rukh-khan-to-reunite-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-after-22-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plan Your Gulmarg And Leh Trips For Khelo India Winter Games 2024</title>
		<link>/plan-your-gulmarg-and-leh-trips-for-khelo-india-winter-games-2024/</link>
					<comments>/plan-your-gulmarg-and-leh-trips-for-khelo-india-winter-games-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 14:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plan Your Gulmarg And Leh Trips For Khelo India Winter Games 2024]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Come February 2, 2024, Gulmarg, Kashmir, will be hosting the fourth edition of the much-awaited Khelo India Winter Games. If reports are to go by, all concerned departments are working to ensure all facilities meet international standards. As per the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Come February 2, 2024, Gulmarg, Kashmir, will be hosting the fourth edition of the much-awaited Khelo India Winter Games. If reports are to go by, all concerned departments are working to ensure all facilities meet international standards. As per the reports, the success of past editions has helped transform Jammu and Kashmir into a winter sports hub. Sports in India are more than cricket. And keeping this in mind, the Khelo India initiative was launched by the Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports. Ever since its launch in 2021, Khelo India has been a game-changer, fostering a culture of sports and fitness across the country. While the summer edition of Khelo India has gained widespread recognition, the Winter Games component is slowly carving its niche, bringing forth not only the hidden talents in winter sports, but also the destinations associated with it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Khelo India Winter Games focuses on sports like ice hockey, cross-country, skiing, and snowboarding. Interestingly, though the northern states like Jammu and Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh, and Uttarakhand naturally have a stronghold in winter sports, several athletes from states that are not traditionally associated with cold weather sports have been making their mark. The Winter Games encompass a variety of disciplines. Ice hockey, cross-country, skiing and snowboarding in particular have been tremendously impressive. It’s not just sports enthusiasts, but travellers from all over India and abroad have made it to the games to witness the adrenaline-pumping sports.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Khelo India Winter Games is also a great opportunity to showcase the rich culture and warm hospitality of the Union Territories of Jammu and Kashmir and Ladakh. As per the Sports Authority of India (SAI), the 4th Edition of Khelo India Winter Games 2024 will be held from February 2 to 6, 2024, in two Union Territories of Jammu &amp; Kashmir and Ladakh. The event will feature competitions across seven sports, and with participation from 860 athletes, in two venues – Gulmarg and Leh. At the moment, Gulmarg is experiencing a snowless winter which makes one wonder about the winter games. But one can still hope for the much-awaited (and timely) snow in Gulmarg for the exciting Khelo India Winter Games.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/plan-your-gulmarg-and-leh-trips-for-khelo-india-winter-games-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluesky Is No Longer Invite-only</title>
		<link>/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/</link>
					<comments>/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluesky Is No Longer Invite-only]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bluesky, a micro-blogging platform founded by Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey, has officially opened its doors to the public after nearly a year as an invite-only app. With an initial user base of 3 million sign-ups during its closed beta phase,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Bluesky, a micro-blogging platform founded by Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey, has officially opened its doors to the public after nearly a year as an invite-only app. With an initial user base of 3 million sign-ups during its closed beta phase, the social media app features an open-source decentralised infrastructure. Bluesky&#8217;s user interface closely resembles that of Twitter, providing a familiar experience for users. However, the platform&#8217;s true innovation lies in its decentralised infrastructure. The AT Protocol, originally developed within Twitter, has been designed to create a decentralised environment for social networking. This decentralised approach allows for greater transparency and flexibility, as the entire codebase of Bluesky is open source.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Being open source means that anyone, including developers outside the company, can access and scrutinise the code. According to the platform, this transparency fosters trust among users and provides insights into the platform&#8217;s inner workings. Additionally, developers have the freedom to contribute to the project and even build their applications or features on top of the AT Protocol.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While the open-source, decentralised platform has its notable perk over other notably newer micro-blogging platforms Mastodon and Threads, it has a long way to go in building a user base that can sufficiently rival such platforms. However, with the recent shift to now being open to everyone, the open-source AT Protocol codebase is expected to attract third-party developers that might redefine the micro-blogging landscape as we know it. You can sign up for Bluesky by going here, registering via your email, and verifying with your phone number. However, please note that at the time of writing, Bluesky is unable to send verification messages to phone numbers in Bangladesh.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Did you know an Indian startup 3D-printed a house in 21 days</title>
		<link>/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/</link>
					<comments>/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Did you know an Indian startup 3D-printed a house in 21 days]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 27, 2021, Tvasta, a startup founded by alumni from the Indian Institute of Technology Madras, completed the construction of India&#8217;s first 3D-printed house, in only 21 days. Modules for this 500 sq. ft. house were printed in the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">On April 27, 2021, Tvasta, a startup founded by alumni from the Indian Institute of Technology Madras, completed the construction of India&#8217;s first 3D-printed house, in only 21 days. Modules for this 500 sq. ft. house were printed in the startup&#8217;s facility in Chennai and assembled at the site, as per the company&#8217;s official website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How was this done?</strong><br />
The house was built using 3D-printed modules, using a process that involves layer-by-layer deposition of materials to create three-dimensional structures. Such processes typically utilise large-scale 3D printers capable of handling construction materials such as concrete, polymers, or other suitable building materials. According to Tvasta, 3D printing for construction leads to an 80% reduction in waste, and can significantly reduce labour requirements and time of construction.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Google News LinkFor all latest news, follow The Daily Star&#8217;s Google News channel.</strong><br />
The construction of this unique structure cost Rs 5 to 5.5 lakh, which, is about 20% of the cost of a standard 2BHK apartment in India, as per a 2022 report by the Indian news portal The Better India. The report adds that the technology used by Tvasta creates only 1/3rd of the waste generated using conventional building methods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tvasta: vision and goals</strong><br />
According to Tvasta&#8217;s website, the startup was founded with the vision of &#8220;leveraging 3D printing technology to revolutionise home construction&#8221;. In an interview with The Better India, Adithya VS, co-founder and CEO of the startup, noted that by using a 3D printer capable of receiving instructions on building large-scale structures in the form of a 3D virtual file, &#8220;a large-scale structure can be built without formwork or moulds in a very short period through layer-by-layer manufacturing&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a similar interview, Vidyashankar C, COO of Tvasta, said that the startup enables &#8220;mass customisation of end components&#8221; and that by using their 3D printing technology, any construction project can be done in minimum time with minimum impact on the environment. As per their website, the startup plans to &#8220;develop category-creating platform technologies that aim to disrupt the construction industry by automating 80% of construction&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3D-printed statue</strong><br />
&#8216;Anant Siras&#8217;, a 21-foot statue, was printed, assembled, and finished by Tvasta in a month. They have also built &#8216;Anant Siras&#8217; a 21-foot statue commemorating 75 years of India Cement, which was printed, assembled, and finished in a month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rumoured PSP2 Might Offer PS4 and PS5 Games</title>
		<link>/rumoured-psp2-might-offer-ps4-and-ps5-games/</link>
					<comments>/rumoured-psp2-might-offer-ps4-and-ps5-games/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 15:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rumoured PSP2 Might Offer PS4 and PS5 Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PlayStation is reportedly in the process of developing a successor to the PSP, which will offer compatibility with PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 games, as per a YouTuber named Moore&#8217;s Law Is Dead, known for making content on tech. He...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">PlayStation is reportedly in the process of developing a successor to the PSP, which will offer compatibility with PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 games, as per a YouTuber named Moore&#8217;s Law Is Dead, known for making content on tech. He recently shared details about the rumoured device on his YouTube channel, which has over 171,000 subscribers. According to Moore&#8217;s sources, the console is still in the early stages of development, with a potential release at least two years away and AMD is also working on its development. One of the most intriguing aspects of these rumours is the device&#8217;s alleged capability to run games from both the PS4 and PS5 libraries.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The original PlayStation Portable (PSP), made waves in the gaming industry upon its release in the mid-2000s. It marked PlayStation&#8217;s entry into the handheld console market and emerged as a significant competitor to Nintendo&#8217;s DS series. With approximately 80 million units sold, the PSP has had considerable success. However, since then, PlayStation and Sony have not made significant developments in the realm of handheld gaming consoles. PlayStation&#8217;s most recent foray into handheld gaming, the Portal, was launched in November last year. However, it requires ownership of a PS5 console to function, limiting its accessibility to a subset of players.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/rumoured-psp2-might-offer-ps4-and-ps5-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
